Cornell University commencement programs and class printed materials, 1869-2016
Cornell University commencement programs and class printed materials,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University commencement programs and class printed materials, 1869-2016.
37-8-346
Cornell University.
5.5 cubic ft., 288.4 GB
Announcements, invitations, tickets, programs, dance cards, handbooks, directories, class statistics, schedules, broadsides, periodicals, and other materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Included are announcements, invitations, tickets, programs, dance cards, handbooks, directories, class statistics, schedules, broadsides, periodicals, and other printed items relating to class activities such as balls, Class Day celebrations, athletic events, lectures, and other campus events. Commencement and baccalaureate materials include invitations, admission tickets, dance cards, programs, lists of degree candidates, and other items pertaining to ceremonies held by various colleges of the university.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Included are announcements, invitations, tickets, programs, dance cards, handbooks, directories, class statistics, schedules, broadsides, periodicals, and other printed items relating to class activities such as balls, Class Day celebrations, athletic events, lectures, and other campus events. Commencement and baccalaureate materials include invitations, admission tickets, dance cards, programs, lists of degree candidates, and other items pertaining to ceremonies held by various colleges of the university.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Cornell University--Students.
Subjects:
College students.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
Arranged chronologically by class year.
CONTAINER LIST
- Class of 1869, July 1, 1869 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Commencement program and tickets
- Class of 1870, June 30, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Commencement invitation, Commencement program, and tickets
- Class of 1871, June 22, 1871 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Class Day program, Commencement invitation, Commencement program, Candidates for graduation, and tickets
- Class of 1872, June 27, 1872 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Survey, Class day program and papers, Directory of the Cornell University, Commencement program, Members of the Class of 1873, and tickets
- Class of 1873, June 26, 1873 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Promenade Concert invitation, Commencement invitation, Commencement program, "The Glory of Young Men" (a sermon preached by Rufus P. Stebbins at Commencement), and tickets
- Class of 1874, July 2, 1874 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Class Day program, Promenade Concert, Graduation Banquet, Commencement program, List of students, and tickets
- Class of 1875, June 17, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Class of 1876, June 15, 1876 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Class Day program and tickets, Class Day "the Souvenir," Commencement program, and tickets
- Class of 1877, June 21, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Class Day Invitation, Class Day program and tickets, Class Day "the Souvenir," and Commencement invitation
- Class of 1878, June 20, 1878 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Class Day exercises, Commencement invitation, Commencement program, tickets, "The Glory of Youth" delivered by Rev. Henry W. Bellows, D.D., and Statistics of the Class of 1878
- Class of 1879, June 19, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Commencement program
- Class of 1880, June 17, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Class Day invitation, Class Day tickets, Commencement concert program, Commencement invitation, Commencement programs, and tickets
- Class of 1881, June 16, 1881 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Class Day program, Commencement program, and tickets
- Class of 1882, June 15, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Class Day invitation, tickets, Class Day program, and Commencement program
- Class of 1883, June 21, 1883 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Class Day invitation, Class Day program, Commencement program, and tickets, and Photograph list
- Class of 1884, June 19, 1884 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Class Day program, Commencement program, Photograph list, and Candidates for graduation
- Class of 1885, June 18, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Class Day program, tickets, and Commencement program
- Class of 1886, June 17, 1886 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Class Day program, Class Day tickets, and Commencement program
- Class of 1887, June 16, 1887 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Class Day program and Commencement program
- Class of 1888, June 21, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Class Day invitation, Class Day program, and Commencement program
- Class of 1888, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Commencement visitors signature book
- Class of 1888, June 21, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  "Class Day Exercises" Booklet and Commencement program (2 copies)
- Class of 1889, June 20, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Class of 1890, June 19, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Class of 1891, June 18, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Class of 1891, June 18, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Class of 1892, June 16, 1892 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  Class Day invitation and Commencement program
- Class of 1893, June 15, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  Class Day program, Class Day "Souvenir," and Commencement program
- Class of 1894, June 21, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  Class day program, Class Day ticket, and Commencement program
- Class of 1895, June 20, 1895 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Class of 1896, June 18, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Class of 1897, June 17, 1897 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  Class Day program, Baccalaureate Services, and Commencement program
- Class of 1898, June 16, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Class of 1899, June 22, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  Class Day program, Baccalaureate Services, Cornell Songs for Commencement Week, Commencement program, and tickets
- Class of 1900, June 21, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  Class Day program, The Calendar Commencement Number, Baccalaureate Services, Commencement invitation, program, and tickets
- Class of 1901, June 20, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  Class Day program (2 copies), Baccalaureate Services, and Commencement Program
- Class of 1902, June 19, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Class of 1903, June 18, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  Class Day program (2 copies), invitation to commencement exercises, Annual Commencement program
- Class of 1904, June 23, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  Class Day program (2 copies), Booklet listing members of class, and Commencement program
- Class of 1904, June 23, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  Class Day program
- Class of 1905, June 22, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  Class Day program (5 copies), Cornell Songs for Commencement Week, Baccalaureate Services in Sage Chapel, and Commencement program
- Class of 1906, June 21, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  Class Day program, Commencement description, program, and invitations
- Class of 1907, June 20, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  Class Day program, Booklet of Things Cornell, and Commencement program
- Class of 1908, June 18, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  Class Day program, Cornell Songs, Baccalaureate Services, Commencement program and commencement invitation
- Class of 1909, June 17, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  Booklet of Things Cornell, Baccalaureate Services, and Commencement program
- Class of 1910, June 23, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  Class Day program, Baccalaureate Services, Cornell songs, Commencement instructions, and program
- Class of 1911, June 22, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Class of 1912, June 13, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Class of 1913, June 18, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Class of 1914, June 17, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Class Day program, Flyer for Commencement tickets, Baccalaureate Sermon delivered by William Pierson Merrill, and Commencement program
- Class of 1915, June 16, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Class Day program, Commencement instructions, and Commencement program
- Class of 1916, June 21, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Class Day program, Baccalaureate Service ticket, and Commencement program
- Class of 1917, June 27, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Class of 1918, May 22, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Class of 1919, June 23, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Class of 1920, June 23, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Class of 1921, June 22, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Commencement program, Senior Week program
- Class of 1922, June 21, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Baccalaureate Services and Commencement program; Senior Week program
- Class of 1923, June 18, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Baccalaureate Service, Commencement program, and invitation; Senior Week program
- Class of 1924, June 16, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Baccalaureate Service, Commencement instructions, and program
- Class of 1925, June 15, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Class Day program, Class Day invitation, and Commencement program
- Class of 1926, June 14, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Baccalaureate Service, Commencement program, and instructions
- Class of 1927, June 13, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Order of Processing and Commencement program
- Class of 1928, June 18, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Baccalaureate Service, Commencement flyer, program, and invitations
- Class of 1929, June 17, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Baccalaureate Service and Commencement program
- Class of 1930, June 16, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Class of 1931, June 15, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Class of 1932, June 20, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  Baccalaureate Service, Commencement program, List of degrees conferred, and invitations
- Class of 1933, June 19, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Class of 1934, June 18, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Class of 1935, June 17, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Class of 1936, June 15, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Class of 1937, June 21, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Class of 1938, June 20, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  Commencement program and Senior Week program
- Class of 1938, June 20, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Class of 1939, June 19, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Class of 1940, June 17, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Class of 1941, June 16, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  Baccalaureate Service and Commencement programs, date announcement card, Senior Week program
- Class of 1942, May 25, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  Commencement Exercises and Commencement program
- Class of 1943, May 24, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Class of 1944, June 25, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Instructions for Commencement Day and Official List of Degrees Conferred
- Class of 1945, June 24, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Instructions for Commencement Day, Commencement program, and Official List of Degrees Conferred
- Class of 1946, June 23, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Official List of Degrees Conferred
- Class of 1947, June 16, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Commencement program and senior week booklet
- Class of 1948, June1425, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Class of 1949, June 13, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Information concerning Commencement Events, Baccalaureate Service, Degrees Conferred, and Commencement program
- Class of 1950, June 12, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Degrees Conferred and Commencement program
- Class of 1951, June 11, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Class of 1952, June 9, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Information concerning Baccalaureate Service and Commencement Exercises, Degrees Conferred, and Commencement program
- Class of 1953, June 15, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Class of 1954, June 14, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  Commencement notes and Commencement program
- Class of 1955, June 13, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  Baccalaureate Service, Commencement notes, and Commencement program
- Class of 1956, June 10, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  Information concerning the Baccalaureate Service and Commencement Exercises, Commencement Notes, Baccalaureate Service, and Commencement program
- Class of 1957, June 10, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Class of 1958, June 16, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Class of 1959, June 15, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  Commencement at Cornell, Commencement program, and invitation
- Class of 1960, June 13, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Class of 1961, June 12, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  Baccalaureate Service and Commencement Exercises at Cornell and Commencement program
- Class of 1962, June 11, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Class of 1963, June 10, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  Baccalaureate Service and Commencement Exercises at Cornell, Baccalaureate Service, and Commencement program
- Class of 1964, June 15, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Class of 1965, June 14, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Class of 1966, June 13, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  Baccalaureate Service, Commencement program, and Commencement addresses by James A. Perkins
- Class of 1967, June 12, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  Commissioning of Officers and Commencement program
- Class of 1968, June 15, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  "Uncritical Lovers, Unloving Critics" Commencement address by John W. Gardner and Commencement program
- Class of 1969, June 9, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  Commencement address by James A. Perkins and Commencement program
- Class of 1970, June 8, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  Instructions for the Academic Procession and the Commencement Ceremonies, Order of Proceedings for those taking part in the Conferring of Degrees, and Commencement Exercises and Investiture of the President
- Class of 1971, June 7, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  Instructions for the Procession and the Commencement Ceremonies and Commencement program
- Class of 1972, May 26, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Class of 1973, June 9, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  Instructions for the Academic Procession and the Commencement Ceremonies, Commencement program, and invitations
- Class of 1974, June 3, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Class of 1975, June 2, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Class of 1976, May 28, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Class of 1977, May 30, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  For Alumni of Cornell, Instructions for the Academic Procession and the Commencement Ceremonies, and Commencement program
- Class of 1978, May 29, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Class of 1979, May 28, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Class of 1980, May 26, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  List of those receiving degrees and Commencement program
- Class of 1981, May 31, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Class of 1982, May 30, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Class of 1983, May 29, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Class of 1984, May 27, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Class of 1985, June 2, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Class of 1986, June 1, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Commencement program and ILR Diploma Presentation Ceremony
- Class of 1987, May 31, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  Instructions for the Academic Procession and the Commencement Ceremonies, Cornell Class of 1987 Convocation program, and Commencement program
- Class of 1988, May 29, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Class of 1989, May 28, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  ILR Diploma Presentation Ceremony, Baccalaureate Service, ILR Advanced Degree Diploma Presentation Ceremony, Convocation program, and Commencement program
- Class of 1990, May 27, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Instructions for the Academic Procession and the Commencement Ceremonies, Baccalaureate Service, ILR Annual Graduation, PhD Recognition Ceremony Program, Commencement Information Brochure, Commencement Ritual Booklet, and Commencement program
- Class of 1991, May 26, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Johnson Graduate School Commencement Ceremony Program, Commencement Information Brochure, and Commencement program
- Class of 1992, May 24, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Commencement Information Brochure, Commencement Ritual Book, Commencement severe weather ceremony tickets, Commencement invitation, Commencement program, and ILR Annual Graduation program
- Class of 1993, May 30, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  Commencement PhD Recognition Ceremony program, Commencement Ritual Book, Baccalaureate Service, ILR Annual Graduation program, Commencement Weekend Facilities Plan, Commencement program, and Commencement invitation
- Class of 1994, May 29, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  Merrill Presidential Scholars Convocation, Commencement information brochure, Commencement Ritual Book, Commencement invitation, PhD Recognition Ceremony, and Commencement program
- Class of 1995, May 28, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  Merrill Presidential Scholars Convocation, Commencement Information Brochure, Graduate Breakfast Reception invitation, Commencement Ritual Book, PhD Recognition Ceremony program, Baccalaureate Service, and Commencement program
- Class of 1996, May 26, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  Commencement information brochure, Doctoral/Masters Candidates/Science and Technology Studies Major/Biology and Society Major Conferring of the Diplomas and Certificates, Reception for January Graduates program, Commencement invitation, Commencement Ritual Book, and Commencement program
- Class of 1997, May 25, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  Merrill Presidential Scholars Convocation, Commencement Information Brochure, Commencement Breakfast Reception invitation, PhD Recognition Ceremony invitation, Graduating Fellows pamphlet, College and School Receptions list, Doctoral/Masters Candidates/Science and Technology Studies Major/Biology and Society Major Conferring of the Diplomas and Certificates, and Commencement program
- Class of 1988, May 24, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  Doctoral/Masters Candidates/Science and Technology Studies Major/Biology and Society Major Conferring of the Diplomas and Certificates, Commencement Information Brochure, ILR Commencement brochure, Registration for Commencement Regalia, and Commencement program
- Class of 1999, May 30, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  Merrill Presidential Scholars Convocation, Commencement Information Brochure, Commencement invitation, and Commencement program
- Class of 2000, May 28, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  Merrill Presidential Scholars Convocation, PhD Recognition Ceremony, Commencement Ritual Book, Commencement invitation, Commencement Information Brochure, and Commencement program
- Class of 2001, May 27, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  Commencement Information Brochure and Commencement program
- Class of 2002, May 26, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  Baccalaureate Service ticket, PhD Recognition Ceremony, Convocation program, Commencement invitation, Commencement Information Brochure, Commencement video, Ritual Book, Commencement Weekend Facilities Plan, and Commencement program
- Class of 2003, May 25, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  Convocation program, Commencement Weekend Facilities Plan, PhD Recognition Ceremony, Severe Weather Ceremony Tickets, Commencement invitation, Ritual Book, and Commencement program
- "134th Commencement, May 26, 2002", 2002; V-825 (Box 4)
- Class of 1873, Candidates for Graduation, 1873 (Box 5)
- Class of 1911, Baccalaureate and Commencement broadside; June 8-10, 1911 (Box 5)
- Class of 1964, The Cornell Daily Sun Commencement issue (Box 5)
- Class of 2004, Flyer for Senior Convocation Address speaker, Bill Clinton; May 29, 2004 (Box 5)
- Class of 2004, Flyer for Rare and Manuscript Collections' hours during Commencement; May 29, 2004 (Box 5)
- Class of 2011, The Cornell Daily Sun Commencement issue (Box 5)
- Class of 2004, May 30, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Baccalaureate Service, Convocation program, Hotel Dining Options for Commencement, and Commencement program
- Class of 2005, May 29, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  Commencement Information Brochure, PhD Recognition Ceremony, and Ritual Book
- Class of 2006, May 28, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Ritual Book, PhD Recognition Ceremony, Commencement invitation, Commencement Information Brochure, Graduation Products and Information, Grad Pack, Parent Packet with college dean letters included, Student Packet, Commencement program, Commencement address by Hunter R. Rawlings III, Commencement Press Release, and Cornell Chronicle (May 25) relating Commencement details
- Class of 2007, May 27, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  Commencement Weekend Information, Ritual Book, Commencement DVD, Commencement program, Commencement press release, and Commencement address by David J. Skorton
- Class of 2008, May 25, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  Commencement Weekend Information, Ritual Book, Commencement Address by David J. Skorton, and Commencement program
- Class of 2009, May 24, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  Commencement Weekend Information, PhD Recognition Ceremony, Ritual Book, and Commencement program
- Class of 2010, May 30, 2010 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  Ritual Book, PhD Recognition Ceremony, Commencement Weekend Student Checklist and Family Information, and Commencement program
- Class of 2011, May 29, 2011 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Commencement mailed family packet, Commencement invitation from each college, Diploma Frame and Gift Guide, Severe Weather Tickets, Commencement Weekend Student Checklist and Family Information, PhD Recognition Ceremony program, PhD Recognition Ceremony ticket, Ritual Book, and Commencement program
- Class of 2012, May 29, 2012 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Class of 2014, 2014-05 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  College of Veterinary Medicine Hooding Ceremony and Student Awards Programs
- Convocation and Commencement videos, May, 2016; A162-07-001